M1080高清电影 https://M1080.com 提供
西部世界
第一季  第一集
把她唤醒
Bring her back online.
听得到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
是的
Yes.
抱歉  我感觉不太好
I'm sorry. I'm not feeling quite myself.
去掉口音
You can lose the accent.
你知道你身在何处吗
Do you know where you are?
我在梦里
I'm in a dream.
没错  德洛丽丝  你在梦里
That's right, Dolores. You're in a dream.
你想从梦里醒来吗
Would you like to wake up from this dream?
是的
Yes.
我很害怕
I'm terrified.
没什么可怕的  德洛丽丝
There's nothing to be afraid of, Dolores,
只要你答对我的问题就可以了
As long as you answer my questions correctly.
-明白了吗  -是的
- Understand? - Yes.
很好
Good.
第一个问题
First...
你是否质疑过你眼中现实世界的本质
Have you ever questioned the nature of your reality?
没有
No.
告诉我  你对你的世界的看法
Tell us what you think of your world.
有人选择看到这个世界上的丑恶
Some people choose to see the ugliness in this world.
那些无秩序的混乱
The disarray.
我选择看到美好
I choose to see the beauty.
早上好  爸爸  睡得好吗
Morning, daddy. You sleep well?
很好
Well enough.
你要出去写生吗
You headed out to set down some of this natural splendor?
是的
Thought I might.
我相信我们的生命有着某种秩序
To believe there is an order to our days,
某个目标
A purpose.
你对客人有什么看法
What do you think of the guests?
你是说新住民吗
You mean the newcomers?
第一次来的时候我全程演个好人
Now, the first time I played it white hat.
我家人也一起来了
My family was here.
我们一起去钓鱼  去山里淘金
We went fishing, did the gold hunt in the mountains.
-上一次呢  -一个人来的
- And last time? - I came alone.
变身大魔头
Went straight evil.
那是我一生中最棒的两个星期
It was the best two weeks of my life.
我记得父亲对我的教导
I like to remember what my father taught me.
在某个时刻
That at one point or another,
我们都是这个世界的新住民
we were all new to this world.
那些新住民跟我们一样  只是为了寻找
The newcomers are just looking for the same thing we are--
一个自由的地方
A place to be free
一个可以界定梦境
to stake out our dreams,
有着无限可能的地方
a place with unlimited possibilities.
老天  这真是太不可思议了
Oh, god, it's incredible.
当然要物超所值
Better be for what we're paying.
心狠手辣的杀人犯赫克托・艾斯卡顿
Murderous son of a bitch named Hector Escaton
枪杀了警察局长
gunned down the marshal.
躲去山里了
He's holed up in the mountains.
你
You there.
你看起来是个有勇气的小伙子
You look like the kind of man who'd put his mettle to it.
今天可不行  治安官  抱歉
Not today, sheriff. Apologies.
黑麦威士忌
Rye whiskey.
干嘛
What about it?
装在瓶子里没人喝也没什么用
Well, it ain't doing any good sitting in that bottle.
你是新来的
You're new.
细皮嫩肉的
Not much of a rind on you.
给你打个折吧
I'll give you a discount.
无意冒犯  不过
Well, no offense, but...
我更情愿赢得女士的芳心  而不是花钱买
I'd rather earn a woman's affection than pay for it.
爱情总归是要花钱的  亲爱的
You're always paying for it, darling.
区别在于  我们的收费
The difference is our costs
是明码标价挂在门前的
are fixed and posted right there on the door.
你觉得你的世界里有矛盾吗
Do you ever feel inconsistences in your world?
有反复吗
Or repetitions?
每个生命都有其特定的轨道
All lives have routine.
我的并没有什么不同
Mine's no different.
然而  我总是止不住好奇
Still, I never cease to wonder at the thought
会不会有那么一天  一次机缘巧合
that any day the course of my whole life
就会改变我整个人生的方向
could change with just one chance encounter.
别管我
Don't mind me.
只是想表现下骑士风度
Just trying to look chivalrous.
你回来了
You came back.
我说过我会回来的
I told you I would.
我能送你回家吗
Can I see you home?
那得看你跟不跟得上了
Well, that all depends. Can you keep up?
我还得去牵我的马
Well, I have to fetch my horse.
那你最好快一点
Better fetch him fast.
景色真美
That's a beautiful sight.
一直不明白
Never understood how you
你怎么能让它们都往一个方向走
keep them all headed in the same direction.
我忘了你是一个光装相
I forget you dress like a cowboy,
不放牛的牛仔
but that's about the extent of it.
看见那头了吗
See that one?
-嗯  -那是头牛朱达斯
- Yeah. - That's the Judas steer.
你让他去哪儿  牛群都会跟着过去
Rest will follow wherever you make him go.
你是怎么把它选出来的
How do you pick him out?
知道点技巧罢了
Just know these things.
就像我还知道你一定会回来的
Same as I knew you'd be back.
你是说我很好猜
You saying I'm predictable?
每个人都有自己的路
There's a path for everyone.
你的路指引你回到我身边
Your path leads you back to me.
我知道万物皆有定数
I know things will work out the way they're meant to.
就像我还知道爸爸看到你会不高兴
Same as I know my daddy still won't be happy to see you.
父亲不会这么晚让它们在外边乱跑的
Father wouldn't let them roam this close to dark.
待着别动  德洛丽丝
Stay put, Dolores.
你这里除了牛奶
Ain't you got anything out here
就没有别的了吗  老头
Other than milk, old man?
动手吧
Go ahead.
我不急着去见阎王
I'm in no rush to meet my judgment,
但我很清楚你将面临的下场  你这混...
but I'm more sure of the outcome than you, you son of a--
那就是只有牛奶了
Nothing but milk, then.
真可惜  我们都没来得及上
Shame of it is you killed the old woman
你就把那老女人杀了
before any of us could have a turn.
我看她还暖和着呢
I reckon she's still warm enough.
没人会说三道四的
Nobody gonna judge you for it.
该死  该死  该死
Oh, shit. Shit, shit, shit.
最后一个问题  德洛丽丝
Last question, Dolores.
如果我告诉你  你是错的呢
What if I told you that you were wrong?
这里没有什么机缘巧合
That there are no chance encounters?
你  和你熟知的每一个人
That you and everyone you know
都是被创造出来为那些
were built to gratify the desires
花钱来到你们世界的人们满足欲求的
of the people who pay to visit your world?
爸爸
Daddy!
爸爸  不
Daddy! No!
那些人被你叫做"新住民"
The people you call "The newcomers."
又见面了
Hello again.
你爸爸放弃得真快
Your daddy gave it up quickly.
感觉他越来越差劲了
Think he's losing his touch.
你就要随他而去了  你这混蛋
You'll be following right behind him, you son of a bitch.
这就是你对待老朋友的方式吗
Is that any way to treat an old friend?
我来这里反复三十年了
I've been coming here for 30 years,
但是你依然不记得我  是不是
But you still don't remember me, do you?
我们一起经历过那么多
After all we've been through.
他们给你增加了点勇气  德洛丽丝
They gave you a little more pluck, Dolores.
真是太迷人了
Absolutely charming.
别用你的脏手碰她
Take your hands off her.
泰迪
Oh, Teddy.
学了什么新招数吗
Any special tricks for us?
他们教了你坐直  还是作揖讨食
They teach you to sit up, beg?
不如我让你先开枪吧
How about I give you the first shot, hmm?
毕竟  死狗也有翻身的时候
After all, every dog has his day.
你的嘴巴倒是动得挺快
Well, your mouth move fast enough.
不知你的枪如何
How about your gun?
如果我告诉你  你不能伤害新住民
What if I told you that you can't hurt the newcomers?
而他们可以对你为所欲为呢
And that they can do anything they want to you?
我从不明白他们为什么要把你们配成一对
I never understood why they paired some of you off.
看起来挺残酷的
Seems cruel.
然后我明白了
And then I realized
胜利要建立在别人输掉的基础上才有意义
winning doesn't mean anything unless someone else loses.
也就是说  你注定要成为输家
Which means you're here to be the loser.
我来帮你一把吧  孩子
Let me help you, son.
看起来你不是你以为的那种人
Seems you're not the man you thought you were.
来吧  美人
Come on, beautiful.
不不  不要
Oh, no! No!
泰迪  泰迪
Teddy! Teddy!
不不不  求你别伤害他
No, no, no, please don't hurt him.
你要什么我都愿意做
I'll do whatever you say.
我花这么多钱可不是为了简简单单取胜
I didn't pay all this money 'cause I want it easy.
我想要你反抗
I want you to fight.
不准碰她
Don't you touch her!
该死的  回来这里的感觉真棒
God damn, feels good to be back.
咱们去庆祝吧
Let's celebrate.
不  不要
No! Don't!
Oh, no, no!
不要
No!
我告诉你的这些事
Would the things I told you
有没有让你改变对新住民的看法  德洛丽丝
change the way you think about the newcomers, Dolores?
不要
No!
没有
No.
当然没有
Of course not.
我们都喜爱新住民
We all love the newcomers.
我遇到的每个新的人
Every new person I meet
都提醒着我  能活着是多么幸运
reminds me how lucky I am to be alive...
这个世界是多么美好
...and how beautiful this world can be.
天啊  他们可真鲜活
Oh, my god, they're so lifelike.
看看那个  他简直完美
Look at that one. He's perfect.
完美等于无聊
Perfect is boring.
我对坏人更感兴趣
I'm more interested in the bad guys.
看到了吗
Did you see it?
没有
No.
再等等  她还会重复
Give it a second. She'll do it again.
她的手指  那不是标准配置手势
Her finger. That's not standard.
我昨晚就注意到了
I noticed it last night.
于是去查了更新文件
Went looking in the update.
是一套新型的手势
It's a whole new class of gestures.
可如果不是我们设置的  那会是谁
But if we didn't put it there, then who did?
福特  他在我们发布更新前还是会一一检查
Ford. He still reviews every update before we issue them.
肯定是他没告诉别人偷偷加进去的
He must have slipped it in there without telling anyone.
他管那叫"冥思"
He calls them "Reveries."
以前的手势只是一般的动作
The old gestures were just generic movements.
-这些是绑定了特定记忆的  -怎么可能
- These are tied to specific memories. - How?
记忆会在每个叙事环结束后被清除
The memories are purged at the end of every narrative loop.
但数据还在  等着被覆盖重写
But they're still in there, waiting to be overwritten.
他找到了方法对它们进行提取
He found a way to access them,
就像某种潜意识
Like a subconscious.
一个有深度的妓女
A hooker with hidden depths?
所有男人的梦想啊
Every man's dream.
就是这些小细节让他们显得真实
It's the tiny things that make them seem real,
让游客爱上他们
That make the guests fall in love with them.
失陪
Excuse me.
出问题了吗
We have a problem?
我们监测到某种非既定活动
We have some unscheduled activity.
显然  你的一个作品不太安分
Evidently, one of your creatures is restless.
在园区里吗
In the park?
不  在冷藏库  地下83层
No, sublevel 83, cold storage.
我们该谨慎处理
We should be cautious.
派个应急小队过去  要全副武装
Send a response team, full armor.
我会亲自去处理
I'll take care of it myself.
我觉得你们跟游客一样享受换装
I think you guys enjoy playing dress up as much as the guests.
接待员没法伤害你们  设定就是如此
The hosts can't hurt you by design.
你家里没有孩子吧  伯纳德
You don't have kids at home, do you, Bernard?
没有
No.
要是你有  你就会知道他们早晚都会叛逆
If you did, you'd know that they all rebel eventually.
你得原谅他们可能有点紧张过度
You'll forgive them for being a little uptight.
每次你的团队运行一次更新
Every time your team rolls out an update,
都有出现重大故障的可能性
There's a possibility of a critical failure.
我们又不会更新冷藏库里的接待员
We don't update the hosts in cold storage
园区也有三十年没出现过重大故障了
And the park hasn't had a critical failure in over 30 years.
早该出故障了
Meaning we're overdue.
我也去  如果是我的作品  我也许能帮上忙
I'll go along, too. If it's one of mine, I might be able to help.
他们正常运作的时候才是你的  伯尼
They're only yours until they stop working, Bernie.
否则他们就是我的
Then they're mine.
地下83层
制冷系统已经坏了几周了
Cooling system's been down for weeks.
气味肯定不错  我建议你退后点
Gonna smell fantastic. I recommend you hang back.
他们什么时候会修好
When are they gonna fix this?
牲畜管理部门还有其他更重要的事
Livestock management's got other priorities.
而且
Besides...
这里又没人抱怨
No one's complained.
敬穿白鞋的女士
Here's to the lady with the white shoes.
卷走了所有的钱  还喝光了所有的酒
Take all your money, drink all your booze.
别
Stop.
除非你打算把老板也废了
Unless you plan to decommission the boss.
没能守身如玉  那算不上罪过
ain't got a cherry, that ain't no sin.
至少身子还在
She's still got the box that the cherry come in.
我要为此喝一杯
I'll drink to that.
辛辣酒
The old coffin varnish.
西部酒吧用威士忌与松节油/氨水/火药/辣椒粉调的重口酒
他们现在已经不做了
They don't make that like they used to.
现在什么都比不上从前了
They don't make anything like they used to.
没错  人也一样
Damn right. Men neither.
我当年看过几次决战
I've seen a few showdowns in my day.
可比你想的还多
More than you know.
我们为穿白鞋的女士干一杯吧
Shall we drink to the lady with the white shoes?
我们还是为了
Perhaps we better drink to a...
一夜无梦的沉睡干一杯吧
Deep and dreamless slumber.
老比尔总是个很好的倾听者
Old Bill here was always a good listener.
他是我们造的第二个接待员
He was the second host we ever built.
那时候你来了吗  伯纳德
Were you with us in those days, Bernard,
还是在你来之前了
Or was that before your time?
恐怕大部分都在我来之前就被废弃了
Most were decommissioned before I was brought on, I'm afraid.
他们一直自我重复  经常坏掉
They repeated themselves, broke down constantly.
一次简单的握手就能让他们暴露本质
A simple handshake would give them away.
你还会把自己放好吧  比尔
You'll put yourself away again, won't you, Bill?
我看到了新的手势  冥思
I saw the new gestures, the reveries.
很优美
They're beautiful.
你这一路来做出的成就
The distance you've traveled from then till now,
很了不起
It's remarkable.
算得上是吧
Yeah, that's a word for it.
早上好  爸爸  睡得好吗
Morning, daddy. You sleep well?
很好
Well enough.
你要出去写生吗
You headed out to set down some of this natural splendor?
是的
Thought I might.
当然得等我放完牛
After my errands, of course.
天黑前回来
See you home before dark.
那个枪杀了警察局长的强盗
That bandit who gunned down the
还藏在山里
marshal is still hiding up there in the hills.
我已经不是小孩子了  没事的
I'm not a child anymore. I'll be just fine.
我当差的时候
When I was a law man--
没错  爸爸  我知道所有你当差时的事
Yes, daddy, I know all about when you were a law man.
我和所有想追我的男孩子
I know all your stories and
都知道你的那些故事
so does every boy that ever came courting.
我知道他们是怎么想的  我也年轻过
I know how boys think. Was one myself once.
经常各种酗酒闹事
Given to all manner of drinking and mischief.
那个无法无天的男孩去哪了
Whatever happened to that fearsome ne'er-do-well?
他在我成为你父亲的那天消失了
He vanished the day I became your father.
是你造就了今天的我
I am what I am because of you,
我也不想成为别的样子
and I wouldn't have it any other way.
我知道  爸爸
I know, daddy.
我会在天黑前回家
I'll be home before dark.
心狠手辣的杀人犯赫克托・艾斯卡顿
Murderous son of a bitch Hector Escaton
枪杀了警察局长
gunned down the marshal.
他现在窝藏在山上
He's now holed up in the mountains.
这位先生
You there.
你看起来很有勇气
You look like the kind of man who'd put his mettle to it.
你觉得呢  亲爱的
What do you think, honey?
听起来很好玩
Sounds fun.
你是新来的
You're new.
细皮嫩肉的
Not much of a rind on you.
给你打个折吧
I'll give you a discount.
无意冒犯  我更情愿赢得女士的芳心
No offense, but I'd rather earn a woman's affection
而不是花钱买
than pay for it.
等等  等等  我认识他
Wait, wait, I know that one.
泰迪
Hey, Teddy.
上次过来  是这哥们带我参观的
Yeah, last trip, this dude showed me around.
怎么了  泰迪
What's the good word, Teddy?
多谢了
Mighty kind of you.
很甜
Sweet.
但不如你甜
Not as sweet as you.
恐怕我今晚另有安排了  德洛丽丝
I'm afraid I've got other plans tonight, Dolores.
祝你今晚愉快
Have a pleasant evening.
你是新来的  细皮...
You're new. Not much of a...
请下注  先生们  请下注
Place your bets, gentlemen. Place your bets.
看来赫克托往这边逃了
Yeah, looks like Hector's been this way.
你知道还要走多久吗
Any idea how much longer this is gonna take?
我妻子不想在天黑后还在山上
My wife doesn't want to be up here after dark.
我们知道他躲在山上某处
We know he's up in these hills somewhere.
他肯定会狠狠和我们干上一场  等我们
He's gonna put up one hell of a fight when we--
等我们  等我们
When we-- when we--
治安官
Sheriff?
他出毛病了  我要回镇上
Something is wrong with it. I want to head back to town.
马上
Now.
这他妈的什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with it?
你给他升了级
You updated the guy,
现在他犯了癫痫
and now he's a six-foot gourd with epilepsy.
到底他妈的怎么回事
So what the fuck happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
这还真是
Well, that's exactly what
我想从编程部门主管嘴里听到的话呢
you want to hear from your head of programming.
我们还没完成诊断
We haven't finished the diagnostic yet.
很明显机器出现了异常行为
Clearly it's exhibiting some aberrant behavior.
真他妈异常啊  伯尼
Pretty fucking aberrant, Bernie.
你的接待员会生病  迷路
Your hosts get sick, they get lost,
但这可就奇怪了
but this is grotesque.
是升级导致的问题吗
Is it a problem with the update?
有可能  但可能性不大
Possible, but not likely.
如果这个版本有问题
If it's the unlikely version,
说说你已经升级了多少接待员
how many hosts have you updated so far?
差不多10%
Maybe 10% of the population.
好吧  弄清问题前把所有升级接待员收回
All right, we pull all updated hosts until we can figure it out.
你他妈的在逗我吗
Are you fucking kidding me?
那可是两百个接待员  涉及十几条故事线
That's 200 hosts spread across a dozen active storylines.
游客们经常会打断你宝贵的故事情节
The guests interrupt your precious storylines all the time
只要他们想射击或者干什么东西的时候
when they want to shoot or fuck something.
不  那是他们想
No, when they want to.
我们提供的是一百个相互关联的故事
We sell complete immersion
沉浸式的旅程
in 100 interconnected narratives.
不间断的体验
A relentless fucking experience.
你抽掉一个角色  整个故事都要调整
Now, you pull one character, the overall story adjusts.
一次性抽掉两百个  这他妈就是大灾难
You pull 200 at once, and it's a fucking disaster!
告诉我哪一半是
Tell me which half is which
我来搜搜那一半
and I'll search that half.
那一半会切断你的喉咙的
Yeah, the half that's gonna cut your fucking throat.
我告诉过你  我没...
I told you, I didn't take--
又和新的一样了  是吗
Good as new again, huh?
有时候我很羡慕你能忘记从前
Sometimes I envy your forgetfulness.
有一个接待员出现了严重故障
We've got a serious problem with one of the hosts.
这个人还没喝够呢
Thinking this one's still thirsty.
这次不会死了  阿诺德
Not gonna die this time, Arnold.
没什么能杀得了我
Ain't nothing gonna kill me.
你们喝不了  这不是给你们的
You can't have none. Ain't for you.
又找到一瓶
Found me another bottle.
你在长个  要多喝奶
You're a growing boy.
你在长个
A growing boy.
在长个
Growing boy!
里面有两个客人
We got two guests inside.
我去跟他们谈
We'll go talk to them,
你们搞定这个烂摊子
you sort this mess out.
他们本就该相互攻击的
You know, they're supposed to turn on each other,
但只有在客人把他们带到高能故事情节上的时候
but only if a guest takes them on the high sierra storyline,
沃尔特总会配合
and Walter always buys it.
看来沃尔特已经厌倦了
Well, I guess Walter got tired of buying it.
这说明治安官的事不是个别事件
I suppose this means the sheriff wasn't an isolated incident.
其实这是个好消息  真的
It's good news, really.
证实了问题就是出自于升级
Confirms the problem was part of the update.
我们可以把他们进行滚回操作
We can roll them back,
清理干净  再重新上线
clean them up, put them back in service.
你觉得我会同意
You think I'm gonna sign off
让这个谋杀犯重新上线吗
On this fucking homicidal thing going back into service?
本来的设计就是谋杀犯
It's homicidal by design.
你想对制造者说些什么
And what do you want to say to your maker?
以肮脏龌龊的匠人之手
By most mechanical and dirty hand...
出自莎士比亚《亨利四世》  梁实秋译本
出自莎士比亚《李尔王》  梁实秋译本
我必对你们痛加报复
I shall have such revenges on you both.
我必定这样做
The things I will do.
究竟做什么我现在还不知道
What they are, yet I know not,
不过总是人间可怕的事
but they will be the terrors of the earth.
你不知道自己在哪里吧
You don't know where you are, do you?
这是你自掘的坟墓
You're in a prison of your own sins.
关掉它
Turn it off.
那是什么
What the hell was that?
我不知道  他脱离剧本了
I don't know. He's off script.
我们没有编写这些行为
We didn't program any of those behaviors.
莎士比亚
Shakespeare.
我们不是让这个接待员扮演过很多不同角色吗
We've used this host in a number of different roles, have we not?
自从我来了这里  十年来他一直是艾伯纳西
Since I've been here, he's been Abernathy for 10 years.
在那之前他做了一阵治安官
He was sheriff for a while before then.
-再之前是  -教授
- And before that... - The professor.
你觉得我们要怎么做
I mean, what do you propose we do?
停业吗  发礼品券吗
Close down? Issue fucking gift certificates?
你的眉毛很美
It's beautiful-- your brow.
当你生气却极力控制的时候  眉毛很美
When you're angry but trying to control it,
肌肉活动使其形成一道弧线
The fine muscles pull into a little arc.
很优美
It's elegant.
我能录下来吗
Would you mind if I recorded it?
我想给我的团队看看
I'd love to show it to my team.
不行  伯纳德  不能录
No, Bernard, you may not record it.
眉毛又动了
Ah, there it is again.
园区内有1400名游客
We have 1,400 guests in the park.
我需要知道他们是否有危险
I need to know if they're in any danger.
他的核心程序很完整
His core code is intact,
也就是说他不会伤害游客
which means he can't hurt a guest.
就连一只苍蝇都不会伤害
He literally couldn't hurt a fly.
他只会...
All he can do is...
这么做
...that.
好吧  伯尼
All right, Bernie.
进行诊断
Run a diagnostic.
同时  哪怕是一个
In the meantime, there's so much
偏离剧本的小喷嚏  都要告诉我
as an unscripted sneeze, I want to know about it.
这地方太他妈疯狂了
This place is fucking wild.
这只是最基本的
This is basic.
第一级
Level one.
你出城后
You ride out of town,
真正的疯狂才刚刚开始
that's when the real demented shit begins.
那时我朋友泰迪就会登场
That's where my man Teddy comes in.
他就像个导游
He's like a guide.
老实说
Honestly,
那家伙让我感觉有点恐怖
the guy kind of creeps me out.
管他的  等他带我们出了峡谷
Fuck it, he leads us out in the canyons,
无聊的时候就拿他当靶子练枪好了
we get bored, we just use him for target practice.
我们不应该过河吧
I don't think we're supposed to be cross the river.
雅各布还太小
It's too adult for Jacob.
我们无意打扰您
We didn't mean to bother you.
不算打扰  这里景色很美
No bother at all. It's a beautiful spot.
我一直觉得不该一个人独享
I always found it a shame that I have it all to myself.
它们每天都会来
They come here every day.
你想靠近点看吗
Would you like a closer look?
别怕  它们很温顺的
Don't be scared. They're very gentle.
给你  手掌摊平
Here, put your hand out real flat.
它们很美吧
They're beautiful, aren't they?
你是他们中的一员  对吧
You're one of them, aren't you?
你不是真实的
You're not real.
我得走了  太阳快下山了
I have to go now. Sun's almost down.
你们也回吧  山里有强盗
You should, too. There's bandits in these hills.
就是这样  驾
Here we go, yah! Yah!
你在等我吗  爸爸
You waiting up for me, daddy?
我跟你说了我会在天黑前回来
I told you I'd be home before dark.
我今天在土里发现了这个
I found this in the field today.
我看不出来什么
Doesn't look like anything to me.
她这是在哪里
Well, where is she?
你见过这种地方吗
Have you ever seen anything like this place?
我看不出来什么
Doesn't look like anything to me.
我去帮妈妈准备晚饭了
I'm gonna help mama put supper on.
我跟你想得一样
I had the same thought.
睡觉之前得晒晒太阳
Needed a little sunshine before turning in.
你下次什么时候轮班回家
So, when do you get to rotate home again?
你这么不会聊天
If you're this bad at writing small talk,
到底是怎么得到这份工作的
How the fuck did you get your job?
说重点
Get to the point.
如果之前多有冒犯  我向你道歉
I wanted to apologize if I came across as aggressive.
还有我想跟你谈谈更新的事
And I wanted to talk to you about the update.
问题已经解决了
The problem's been resolved.
根本就不该有什么更新
There should never have been an update in the first place.
福特和伯纳德一直想把他们弄得更像人类
Ford and Bernard keep making the things more lifelike.
但真的有人想要这样吗
But does anyone truly want that?
你想觉得
Do you want to think that your
你丈夫真的在上某个漂亮女人吗
husband is really fucking that beautiful girl
还是你真的射杀了某个人
or that you really just shot someone?
正因为游客知道接待员不是真人
This place works because the guests
这里才这么受欢迎
know the hosts aren't real.
你到底想说什么
So what exactly are you suggesting?
不要再升级了
Stop the updates altogether.
也许还可以滚回一点
Maybe even roll them back a bit.
让接待员更可控一些
Make the hosts more manageable.
额叶切除手术可以做到
Lobotomies tend to do that.
想想这样的好处吧
Well, think of the benefits
在设计时间  维护  成本上
In terms of design time, maintenance, costs.
就更不用提福特博士了
Not to mention the dr. Ford factor.
这个人会追随他内心的恶魔直至地狱的深渊
The guy's gonna chase his demons right over the deep end.
我比谁都要敬重他  但是在这点上...
I mean, no one respects him more than me, but at some point--
我  没人比我更敬重他
I. No one respects him more than I.
你的代词是第二个分句的主语
Your pronoun is the subject of the second clause.
我是说
I was saying-- -
你说的是我们那个无所畏惧的头儿垮了
you were saying should our fearless leader have a breakdown,
你想利用这个往上爬
you want to leverage it for your career.
听我说  早就应该换人了
Listen, a changing of the guard is long overdue.
我想你知道  我站在你这边
I just wanted you to know that you have my support
而且我知道
and that I know that the
公司对这里的真正兴趣
corporation's real interest in this place
远不止是满足那些
goes way beyond gratifying
想扮演牛仔的有钱混蛋
some rich assholes who want to play cowboy.
我原以为你只擅长
And here I thought you were only good
写写下流的幻想剧情
For writing depraved little fantasies.
没错
You're right.
这个地方对客人是一回事
This place is one thing to the guests,
对股东来说又是另一回事
another thing to the shareholders,
在管理上又是完全不同的
and something completely different to management.
启发启发我
So enlighten me.
你觉得管理层真正的兴趣是什么
What do you think management's real interests are?
你够聪明  能看到存在远景
You're smart enough to guess there's a bigger picture,
但又不够聪明  看不清楚是什么
but not smart enough to see what it is.
所以你知道你的支持对我来说有什么用吗
You know how much use that makes your support to me?
什么用都没有
Fuck all.
去睡个好觉吧  希斯摩尔先生
Get some sleep, Mr. Sizemore.
你明天还要讨好更多的有钱混蛋呢
You'll have more rich assholes to gratify tomorrow.
这么早睡吗  梅芙
Early night, maeve?
身体有点不适
Feeling a bit out of sorts.
克莱门汀可以接我的活
Clementine can pick up the slack.
晚安
Night.
忘了什么吗  基西
Forgetting something, Kissy?
我开始觉得你对我有意思了
I'm beginning to think you're getting sweet on me.
那是因为你身上流着一半乡巴佬的血
Well, on account of you being half cornhusker.
沃尔特一直都杀其他的接待员
Walter kills other hosts all the time.
我承认这个模式
I'll admit the method here
有点打破常规
is a little unconventional,
但是它没有伤害到客人
but it didn't hurt a guest.
接待员理应待在自己的循环中
The hosts are supposed to stay within their loops,
按剧本行事
stick to their scripts
只能有极小的即兴发挥
with minor improvisations.
但这可不是极小的即兴发挥
This isn't a minor improvisation.
这他妈简直是场大灾难
This is a fucking shitstorm.
我们明天必须召回所有被更新的接待员
We recall all remaining updated hosts tomorrow.
一个个检查  废弃掉残次品
Examine them one by one, decommission the faulty ones.
那整个故事线怎么办
What about narrative?
如此大规模的召回  会引发极大的混乱
A recall of that size will be disruptive.
我已经让那位狂暴的朋友
I've told our overstimulated friend
提前一周去洗劫酒吧
to advance the saloon heist a week
并让血腥程度翻倍
and make it twice as bloody.
那应该可以帮我们掩盖召回剩余接待员的行动
Should give us cover to recall the remaining hosts.
客人们一定会很喜欢的
And the guests will love it.
我觉得福特恐怕不会同意吧
I'm not sure Ford will approve.
我也担心他不会同意
I'm not sure either,
因此就由你去告诉他吧
which is why you get to be the one to tell him.
这是你搞出的烂摊子  伯尼
This is your fuckup, Bernie.
只有这样才公平
Only seems fair.
我们的创造物似乎有些行为失常
So our creatures have been misbehaving,
你到现在还没把程序错误筛选出来吗
and you haven't yet isolated the bug?
那可真不像你的风格  伯纳德
That's so unlike you, Bernard.
当然  除非你已经解决了
Unless, of course, you have
只不过是结果让你感到很丢人
and are simply embarrassed by the result.
是您添加的代码出了问题  先生
It's the code you added, sir.
冥思
The reveries.
它有一些...
It has some...
"错误"
"Mistakes"
你觉得很丢人  不想用这个词
Is the word you're too embarrassed to use.
你不必觉得丢人
You ought not to be.
你就是千万亿个错误的产物
You're a product of a trillion of them.
进化形成了这个星球上有情感和知觉的生命体
Evolution forged the entirety of sentient life on this planet
用的唯一的工具  就是错误
using only one tool--the mistake.
我自认为
I flattered myself
我们现在采取的是更专业成熟的做法
we were taking a more disciplined approach here.
我猜"自欺"也是自然选择的结果吧
I suppose self-delusion is a gift of natural selection as well.
确实如此
Indeed it is.
不过  当然了  我们已经成功地
But, of course, we've managed to
摆脱了进化的束缚  对吧
slip evolution's leash now, haven't we?
我们可以治愈任何疾病
We can cure any disease,
让我们当中最弱的人也能活命
keep even the weakest of us alive,
或许  将来有一天
and, you know, one fine day
我们甚至能让亡者复生
perhaps we shall even resurrect the dead.
就像耶稣将拉萨路复活一样
Call forth Lazarus from his cave.
你知道那意味着什么吗
Do you know what that means?
意味着到此结束了
It means that we're done.
这就是我们能取得的最好的结果了
That this is as good as we're going to get.
也意味着
It also means that
你必须迁就我偶尔的错误
you must indulge me the occasional mistake.
大约三公升
About three liters.
那就是我给你留下的血液量
That's how much blood I left in you.
失血再多一点  你就会死
Lose more than that, you die.
但是眼下  你还在我掌心里
But for now, you're mine.
我要从你口中问出一些答案
I'm gonna get some answers out of you.
你这是要去...
Where are you--
你想怎么样
What do you want?
你会玩游戏吧  基西
You know about games, don't you, Kissy?
这就是个复杂点的游戏
Well, this is a complicated one.
我不玩游戏  我只发牌
I don't play. I only deal.
谁说让你玩了
Who said anything about you playing?
你就是牲畜  是布景而已
You're livestock, scenery.
我才是玩家
I play.
其他人  只是来发泄一下性欲
The others, they just come here to get their rocks off,
或是杀几个印第安人的
shoot a couple indians.
但这个游戏还有更深的层次
But there's a deeper level to this game.
你要带我进入那里
You're gonna show me how to get there.
古文化中蕴含了太多的智慧
A lot of wisdom in ancient cultures.
或许...
And perhaps it's...
是时候挖进你的大脑更深层了
Time to dig deeper into yours.
不  不要
No. No. No.
早上好  爸爸  睡得好吗
Morning, daddy. Did you sleep well?
爸爸  你在外面坐了一整晚吗
Daddy, you've been out here all night?
我有个问题
I had a question.
一个不该问的问题
A question you're not supposed to ask.
那让我获知了一个答案
Which gave me an answer
一个你不该知道的答案
you're not supposed to know.
怎么了  爸爸
What's wrong, daddy?
你想知道...
Would you like to know...
那个问题吗
the question?
-问...问题吗  -妈妈
- question? - Mama!
妈妈  快来帮忙
Mama, help! Come quick!
别担心
Don't worry.
别担心  我会照顾好你
Don't worry. I'll take care of you.
不
No!
你该走了  快走
You should go. Leave.
你还不明白吗
Don't you see?
地狱已空  恶魔倾巢而出  来到了这里
Hell is empty and all the devils are here.
来自莎士比亚《暴风雨》
你待在这别动  明白吗
You stay right here. Understand?
我去找医生
I'm gonna find the doctor.
-你回来了  -我说过我会回来的
- You came back. - I told you I would.
-怎么了  -你快跟我来
- What's wrong? - You have to come with me right away.
我父亲病得很重
My father's very ill.
我觉得我们还是先留在原地吧
I think we best stay put.
好吧  好吧
All right. All right.
经过不眠不休的辛勤工作
With considerable effort and lack of sleep,
我终于设法让赫克托
I've managed to massage events to inspire Hector
提前一周来到了镇上
to head to town a week early.
我还写好了等他抢劫酒吧后
Oh, and I've also punched up the speech he gives
要说的一段台词
after robbing the saloon.
相当可怕  你到时候就知道了
It's chilling. You'll see.
我等不及想知道了
I can barely contain myself.
那是治安官的马  你这个混蛋
That's the Sheriff's horse, you son of a bitch.
还有他的枪
His rifle, too.
这儿有那么多银行和火车
All the banks and trains around here,
你们这群恶棍偏偏要来抢我们
and you fucking reprobates choose to rob us?
有何不可
Why not?
你们都在这里放纵你们的罪恶
You're all here indulging your particular vices.
所以我也来放纵我自己
And so I've come to indulge mine.
我得回去找我父亲
I've got to get back to father.
德洛丽丝  不
Dolores, no!
泰迪
Teddy.
别担心我
Don't mind me.
只是想...表现下骑士风度
Just-- just trying to look chivalrous.
泰迪
Oh, Teddy.
你真是个下作的混蛋
You're a low-down son of a bitch.
我知道
I know.
我知道我们有一个相同的理念
I know we both believe the same thing.
不管活多脏
No matter how dirty the business,
都要做好
do it well.
那个保险箱里应该没什么值钱的
No telling there's anything worthwhile in that safe.
我们应该带走这个小贱人
We should take this sweet little bitch
以防万一
just in case.
这就是正义的窘境  他们什么都打不中
Problem with the righteous-- they can't shoot for shit.
不过倒是特别吵
Making a hell of a racket, though.
通缉
赫克托・艾斯卡顿
你们想抓我
You wanted me.
那就给你们上一课吧
Well, let this be a lesson.
那就是
The lesson is--
天
Oh, jesus.
看  我刚打穿了他的脖子
Look at that! I just shot him through the neck!
还有他的同伙
And his pal here, too.
看她抽搐的样子
Look at her wriggle.
叫那个摄影师过来
Yo, go get that photographer.
我要拍张照
I want to get a picture of this.
不客气
You're welcome.
你写的那段台词还是下次再用吧
Maybe you'll get to your speech next time.
泰迪
Oh, Teddy.
至少我最后又见了你一面
At least I got to see you one last time.
你不准死  听到了吗
You're not going anywhere, now, hear?
每个人都有自己的路
There's a path for everyone.
我的路是跟你相连的
My path is bound with yours.
泰迪
Teddy?
泰迪  不
Teddy, no.
求你了
Please.
不  我们才刚开始
No, we've only just begun.
拍得不错  等等  等等
That was good. Hang on. Hang on.
我戴上帽子拍  等我拿帽子
Let me get the hat. Get the hat.
好了
All right.
帮帮我
Help, please.
我父亲在家里生病了
My father's sick at home,
但我不能就这么把他丢在大街上
but I can't just leave him out here in the street.
这很快就会变得像是一场遥远的梦境
Soon this will all feel like a distant dream.
在此之前  愿你陷入一夜无梦的沉睡
Until then, may you rest in a deep and dreamless slumber.
这里还有两个
Two more over here.
全部找到了
We got them all.
全部回收完毕
That's all of them.
有初步结果了吗
Any preliminary results?
大部分检查过都没问题
Most of them are checking out fine.
其中有一个
We had one who...
肯定出了问题
definitely was not.
把她唤醒
Bring her back online.
留下认知能力  去除情感影响
Cognition only. No emotional affect.
亲爱的  听得到我说话吗
All right, sweetheart, can you hear me?
是的
Yes.
抱歉  我感觉不太好
I'm sorry. I'm not feeling quite myself.
去掉口音
Lose the accent.
-你知道你身在何处吗  -我在梦里
- Do you know where you are? - I'm in a dream.
没错  德洛丽丝  你在梦里
That's right, Dolores. You're in a dream.
一个也许能决定你人生的梦
A dream that could determine your life.
你想从梦里醒来吗  德洛丽丝
You want to wake up from this dream, Dolores?
是的
Yes.
我很害怕
I'm terrified.
没什么可怕的
There's nothing to be afraid of,
只要你答对我的问题就可以了
as long as you answer my questions correctly.
-明白了吗   -是的
- You understand? - Yes.
很好
Good.
第一个问题  你是否质疑过你眼中现实世界的本质
First, have you ever questioned the nature of your reality?
没有
No.
你身边的人有过质疑吗
Has anyone around you?
比如说你父亲
For instance, your father?
他很害怕
He was scared.
他的思绪不清晰
He wasn't thinking right.
他给你看了一张照片
He showed you a picture.
是的
That's right.
这张照片有什么异常的地方吗
Was there anything odd about that picture?
完全没有
No, nothing at all.
我看不出来什么
It didn't look like anything to me.
如果它违反规定  就要将其撤下
If it breached, he needs to be put down.
政策就是如此
That's the policy.
对我们来说  先找出原因不是最好的吗
Would it not be best for us to discover why first,
卡伦女士
Ms. Cullen?
请吧
Please.
我们运行了全面诊断
We've run a full diagnostic,
但是结果
but the results are,
令人费解
well, confusing.
告诉我  你的程序出了什么问题
Tell me, what happened to your program?
出自莎士比亚《李尔王》  梁实秋译本
我们一生出来
"When we are born,
我们便哭
we cry we are come
因为我们来到了这个
to this great stage
群丑的台上
of f-f-fools."
可以了
That is enough.
告诉我  你能接入先前的配置吗
Tell me, do you have access to your previous configuration?
是的
Yes.
请接入吧
Access that, please.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
彼得・艾伯纳西先生
Mr. Peter Abernathy.
艾伯纳西先生  你的目标是什么
Mr. Abernathy, what are your drives?
照料我的牲口
Tend to my herd.
照顾我的妻子
Look after my wife.
你的最终目标是什么
Your final drive?
当然是我女儿德洛丽丝
Well, my daughter Dolores, of course.
我必须保护德洛丽丝
I must protect Dolores.
是她造就了我
I am who I am because of her,
我
and, well, I--
我不想成为...
I wouldn't have it--
我不想成为别的...
I-I wouldn't have it any...
别的样子
other--
我必须警告她
I-I have to warn her.
警告谁
Warn who?
德洛丽丝
Dolores.
他们对她做的事
The things they do to her.
The things you do to her.
我必须保护她
I have to protect her.
必须帮她  我
I have to help her. I--
她必须逃出去
She's got to get out.
非常好  艾伯纳西先生
Very good, Mr. Abernathy.
可以了
That's enough.
这种行为
This behavior,
已经远远超出了小故障的范畴
we're miles beyond a glitch here.
请使用当前版本
Access your current build, please.
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
出自美国诗人格特鲁德・斯泰因诗作《圣徒艾米莉》(Sacred Emily)
玫瑰之所以是玫瑰
Rose is a rose...
正因为她是玫瑰
is a rose.
你的行程是什么
What is your itinerary?
去见我的制造者
To meet my maker.
你走运了
Well, you're in luck.
出自于恐怖故事线《晚宴》
Yes, from a horror narrative called "The dinner party."
他是沙漠中一群异教徒的领袖
He was leader of a group of cultists
最终变成了食人族
out in the desert who turned cannibal.
他喜欢引用莎士比亚
He liked to quote Shakespeare,
约翰・邓恩  和格特鲁德・斯泰因
John Donne, Gertrude Stein.
前两者16-17世纪  后者19-20世纪
我承认最后一个年代不太对
I admit the last one is a bit of an anachronism,
但我难以抗拒
but I couldn't resist.
这些是之前版本的记忆碎片
These are fragments of prior builds.
冥思肯定让他接触了这些记忆碎片
The reveries must be allowing him to access them.
没必要紧张  伯纳德
No cause for alarm, Bernard.
只是我们过去的作品有些阴魂不散
Simply our old work coming back to haunt us.
你父亲跟你悄悄说了一些话
Your father whispered something to you.
是什么
What was it?
他让我不要告诉任何人
He said I shouldn't tell anyone.
我不会告诉其他人的
I won't tell anyone else.
我保证
Promise.
他说
He said,
出自莎士比亚《罗密欧与朱丽叶》
这些残暴的欢愉  终将以残暴结局
"These violent delights have violent ends."
这些话对你有什么意义吗
Does that mean anything to you?
没有
No.
我觉得没有
I don't think so.
你对我们撒过谎吗
Have you ever lied to us?
没有
No.
最后一个问题  德洛丽丝
Last question, Dolores.
你会伤害任何生物吗
Would you ever hurt a living thing?
不会
No.
当然不会
Of course not.
请把头往后仰  彼得
Tilt your head back, please, Peter.
数据清除完毕
Wipe's complete.
你觉得这些不会对她的核心代码产生影响吧
You don't think any of that had an impact on her core code?
对亲爱的德洛丽丝不会
Not good old Dolores.
你知道她为什么如此特别吧
You know why she's special?
她被修理了这么多次  基本上算是崭新的
She's been repaired so many times, she's practically brand-new.
别让这点骗了你
Don't let that fool you.
她是乐园里最老的接待员
She's the oldest host in the park.
来吧  亲爱的
Come on, sweetheart.
告诉我们  你对你的世界的看法
Tell us what you think of your world.
这个世界吗
This world?
有人选择看到这个世界上的丑恶
Some people choose to see the ugliness in this world.
那些无秩序的混乱
The disarray.
早上好  爸爸  睡得好吗
Morning, daddy. You sleep well?
很好
Well enough.
你要去接着画你那幅画吗
You heading out to do some more of that painting of yours?
我选择看到美好
I choose to see the beauty.
我相信我们的生命有着某种秩序
To believe there is an order to our days...
某个目标
A purpose.
我知道万物皆有定数
I know things will work out the way they're meant to.